[Music] perfect blueberry
ice cream, nice and cheap,
come with me I'll show you how to make this.
Blueberries are really expensive now, I mean
they've always been pretty expensive but you
can make it with frozen blueberries no
issues whatsoever. Super simple recipe,
we're going to take 100g of frozen blueberries
and we're going to put that on the hob,
just gently because we're going to just
simmer it down a little bit so they've completely
defrosted and reduced that water level back down.
So while that's doing that, let's
get the rest of our ingredients
going because this is nice and easy this
one, we need our milk and our cream what
do we need we need 300g of 2% milk and to
that we're going to add 420g of 33% cream,
as always cups on the screen at the
same time for those that want them,
and into that we are going to add in 55g of skim
milk powder, 35g of corn syrup and then our sugar,
it is 130g of sugar. Into our sugar we are
going to add 1.5g of stabilizer I am going
to use an off-the-shelf stabilizer from Special
Ingredients, not affiliated just have a lot of it.
So 1.5g there and we're going to take a little
mini whisk and stir that together like so and we
are just going to put that in with the rest of
our ingredients like so and this now goes on a
hob. So as the blueberries start to come up to to
a boil like this, we want to with a silicon spoon,
just crush them down. We don't really want
any whole blueberries in here but I'm quite
happy to have the blueberry parts, but what
we want to make sure is that the reduction
starts to take place and for that what it
means is we're trying to just boil off,
which is all this smoke/steam here we're trying
to boil off the excess water or at least some
of it. Frozen anything has got a lot of excess
water in it so we're just going to leave that
for a couple of minutes and whilst that's doing
that, let's turn the heat on for our ice cream.
We're going to just stir all this together
because the corn syrup's in there you're
going to hit a mass of sticky goo down the
bottom just keep stirring it and that bottom
heat will bring that up to temperature and
will come together really nice and quick.
So now our blueberries are coming to a
stage, and what you're looking for is this,
so this kind of consistency. So a
lot of that excess water from the
freezing process has gone and we're
left with a reasonably viscous mix.
Now our ice cream base is starting to come up to
temperature we can look at including our blueberry
syrup, so in that goes, get all of it
in there because it's such a nice color.
Now some people say blueberries taste
like almonds, my wife can't taste that,
I actually can taste that so let me know what you
think blueberries taste like if
anything at all in the comments.
So with that pan out the way move the camera
over and we are just going to continue to mix
this together until we come up to 85°C
/ 185°F. Once it reaches that point,
we can take it off the heat and put it
in a container to completely chill down.
So after the mix is completely
chilled down in the fridge,
we take it out and give it a nice whisk
make sure it's completely homogenized
and then pour it in our pre-chilled ice
cream machine and get that running. After
about 15 to 20 minutes (depending on your
machine) you'll be ready to load it up.
So we've got our store bought marshmallow fluff,
we're going to take a scoop of ice cream put a
spoonful of the fluff and repeat that until
the tub is full then pop it in the freezer.
Here we go, this is the next day, take it out the
freezer have a look at the color.... all natural
purple color it's really really nice, smells like
blueberries, it's delicious got to have the bowl
the right way around and scooping it again you've
just seen me take this out the freezer no magic
effects... Scoops beautifully, marshmallow peeking
out there, oh it's making my mouth water just
looking at it the texture is really good really
really smooth I'm going to zoom in here so you
can have a look and it's lovely and smooth.
Let's see what this tastes like............
blueberry ice cream with a marshmallow swirl,
it's kind of like a marshmallow core rather than
a swirl because I used store bought marshmallow
fluff. You can use your own marshmallow fluff,
It's relatively easy to make I've done it in a
few videos before but when you can just buy this
in the store why not use it. I guess the biggest
problem using store stuff is it's really thick,
it it's very difficult to swirl so you would need
to warm up a little bit to swirl it through......
but great color, smells delicious,
marshmallow just peeking through a
little bit at the top there let's
see what this tastes [Music] like
delicious all natural color no artificial colors,
really really nice texture, no discernable ice
crystals, super smooth, easy to scoop out the
freezer but not too soft. The marshmallow just
adds like another heightened level of sweetness
slightly different texture and actually the
stickiness of the marshmallow in your mouth just
maintains that flavor for a little bit longer.
Frozen blueberries or as I call them
"bloobs" perfect blueberry ice cream,
nice and chea,p hope you enjoyed this one.
Thanks very much for watching don't forget to like
and subscribe and I will see you next time [Music]